They're already here.
War of the Worlds is a adventure, thriller, science
fiction film directed by Steven Spielberg.
Ray Ferrier is a divorced dockworker and less-than-perfect father.
Soon after his ex-wife and her new husband drop off his teenage son and young daughter for
a rare weekend visit, a strange and powerful lightning storm touches down.
Ray Ferrier, played by Tom Cruise.
Rachel Ferrier, played by Dakota Fanning.
Robbie Ferrier, played by Justin Chatwin.
Mary-Ann, played by Miranda Otto.
Harlan Ogilvy, played by Tim Robbins.
Vincent, played by Rick Gonzalez.
War of the Worlds is a 2005 American science fiction action-thriller film directed by
Steven Spielberg and written by Josh Friedman and David Koepp, based on H.
Wells' 1898 novel, The War of the Worlds.
Tom Cruise stars in the main role alongside Dakota Fanning, Miranda
Otto, and Tim Robbins, with narration by Morgan Freeman.
It follows an American dock worker who must look after his estranged children as he struggles to protect and reunite
them with their mother when extraterrestrials invade Earth and devastate cities with giant war machines.
Produced by Paramount Pictures, DreamWorks Pictures, Amblin Entertainment, and Cruise/Wagner Productions, the film was shot in 73 days,
using five different sound stages as well as locations in California, Connecticut, New Jersey, New York, and Virginia.
It was surrounded by a secrecy campaign so few details
would be leaked before its release.
Tie-in promotions were made with several companies, including Hitachi.
War of the Worlds premiered at the Ziegfeld Theatre on June 23, 2005, and
was released theatrically by Paramount Pictures on June 29.
The film received generally positive reviews, with praise for effectively capturing the thrilling and suspenseful
elements of Wells' novel while modernizing the action and effects to resonate with contemporary audiences.
It was also a commercial success, grossing over $603 million worldwide against a $132
million production budget, making it the fourth-most successful film of 2005.
It earned Academy Awards nominations for Best Visual
Effects, Best Sound Mixing and Best Sound Editing.
The film explores themes of daughter, new jersey, post-traumatic
stress disorder (ptsd), airplane, based on novel or book.
The tone is thought_provoking and intense.